ROBERT O'SULLIVAN, ACA

101 Ivy Drive Apt. 2 Charlottesville, Virginia 22903

631-834-1243

OSullivanR12@darden.virginia.edu

SENIOR M&A EXECUTIVE

Accomplished Senior Finance Executive with a record of achievement in mergers, acquisitions, corporate strategy and venture capital. A key player in more than 20 mergers or acquisitions over the past seven years with a composite value of more than \$30B. An experienced accountant, banker and corporate development specialist. Actively involved in the life sciences venture capital community, investing in biotechnology and medical device firms advancing the treatment of diseases.

A global business leader and a qualified accountant under Institute of Chartered Accountants Ireland with a dossier of successful cross-border transactions across jurisdictions including Ireland and UK, Continental Europe, Scandinavia, and the US. Current Full Time Candidate (2010 – 2012) for Master of Business Administration (May 2012) at Darden Graduate School of Business Administration, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA.

Practiced in conducting commercial and financial due diligence on companies in industries including technology, media & telecoms and healthcare (services, pharmaceuticals, biotechnology and medical devices). Adept in building out the company's competitive landscape, reviewing peer companies' product pipelines, and developing a database of relevant transactions. A skilled communicator well versed in the negotiation of securities purchase agreements, employee contracts, non-compete agreements, joint venture agreements, licensing agreements and venture capital investments.

CORE COMPETENCIES

International Business • Joint Ventures • Restructuring • Financial Analysis • Financial Statements M& A • Negotiations • Valuations • Due Diligence • Financial Modeling • Investor Relations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

United Drug plc, Dublin, Ireland and Philadelphia, PA

2007 - 2010

A leading global healthcare services organization with market capitalization in excess of \$1.5B and revenues of \$2.5B. The company has operations in Ireland, the UK, Scandinavia, Continental Europe and the US.

Manager, Group Corporate Development and M&A

Worked in close collaboration with the CEO, Chairman and other senior management to determine the company's investment strategy. Collaborated with divisional management and investment bankers to source potential acquisitions in accordance with group strategy. Secured indications of interest from potential acquisitions' shareholders and management.

Guided all necessary due diligence supporting accurate company valuation, including undertaking of evaluative financial due diligence. Advised senior management on acquisition investment suitability. Directed negotiations with acquisition shareholders. Vetted the efforts of external advisors tasked with conducting financial, tax and legal due diligence. Presented transaction overview to M&A sub-committee of United Drug board for approval. Negotiated securities purchase agreements and other legal documents including employment and non-compete agreements, with shareholders and advisors.

Directed post-merger integration of acquired entities. Facilitated migration of acquired companies to United Drug Group's health insurance plans, treasury and accounting systems and HR systems.

- **Established US operations that contributed 20% to the company's profitability**. Held authority for all North American acquisitions. Established a corporate governance structure as well as the company's US treasury operations. Acted as Finance Director for North American operations and had responsibility for financial control and treasury operations.
- Improved EBIDTA by nearly 20%. Closed 11 transactions across Ireland, the UK, the US, Scandinavia and Continental Europe representing over \$300M in outlay.
- Enabled the company to navigate the worst economic downturn since the 1930's. Restructured and streamlined four United Drug businesses in the US and negotiated with unions over lav-offs and collective bargaining agreements.
- Set the foundation for effective M&A efforts moving forward. Developed a sophisticated acquisition financial valuation model and a due diligence process template model for M&A opportunities.
- Completed first acquisition of public company by United Drug. Negotiated with the Takover Panel (UK-based body) and target financial advisors to ensure deal closed in a timely manner.
- Personally led United Drug's largest acquisition. Completed the 2008 acquisition of Sharp Corporation, which at the time represented United Drug's largest investment and led the deal from sourcing to financial close.

KBC Ireland Finance, Dublin, Ireland and London, United Kingdom 2005 – 2007

The specialized finance (leveraged finance and project finance) unit of KBC Bank, a Belgian-Dutch bank-insurance group and a top-10 Euro bank prior to the sub-prime crisis of 2008. The group focused on telecom, media and technology industries, particularly on telecoms leveraged buy-outs in the EMEA region.

Associate

Analyzed the credit worthiness of potential billion dollar-plus bank lending transactions. Collaborated with senior executives to structure financing solutions. Assisted in negotiation of loan documentation and credit terms with other banks and lenders. Authored information memorandums for syndication purposes and assisted company management and the syndication team in selling underwriting to mitigate bank risk. Trained junior analysts and directed their work.

- Enabled the bank to participate in deal financing underwritten by other firms. Developed and enhanced relationships with private equity firms and other banks to ensure the bank was invited to participate in attractive deals.
- Worked on more than ten telecom related merger or acquisition transactions totaling in excess of \$30B deal size and representing several hundred million dollars of loans outstanding for KBC Finance Ireland.

Ernst & Young, Dublin, Ireland

2002 - 2005

A global firm of chartered accountants and business advisors. The Irish practice had approximately 1,500 staff and revenues of approx. \$100M per annum.

Senior Accountant

Rapidly progressed from trainee accountant to senior accountant while performing audit and tax work for banks, insurance companies, captive finance companies and securitization vehicles. Performed due diligence assignments for various clients. As senior accountant directed the work of as many as ten trainees. Qualified as a chartered accountant in Ireland, the equivalent of a CPA in the United States.

CAREER NOTES

Currently serve as an external advisor to biotechnology startups SphynKx Therapeutics LLC and Diffusion Pharmaceuticals Inc as well as Corporate Development Advisor to NeuroVentures Capital LLC, a venture capital fund investing in companies researching central nervous system diseases. The fund is approx. \$25M in size and has approximately ten portfolio companies.

Position companies to refine product development, protect intellectual property, and secure additional funding. Conduct commercial due diligence, provide intellectual property valuation utilizing dynamic, risk-adjusted financial models. Develop business plans for portfolio companies.

EDUCATION, TRAINING & CERTIFICIATIONS

Candidate for Master of Business Administration (May 2012)

<u>Darden Graduate School of Business Administration, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA</u>

Graduate Certificate Corporate Treasury; Professional Diploma Accounting,

<u>Dublin City University</u>, Dublin, Ireland

Bachelor of Science in Biotechnology, <u>Dublin City University</u>, Dublin, Ireland

Chartered accountant, (ACA, EU equivalent of CPA), Institute of Chartered Accountants Ireland

OF NOTE